<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<E2P xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="e2p_metamodel.xsd">
	<Block>
		<Name>Hardware</Name>
		<Description>Values for hardware setup, which have no special meaning to SHC device concepts + the DeviceType, which decides about the existence of further blocks.</Description>
		<EnumValue>
			<ID>DeviceType</ID>
			<Description>The device can check with this value if the EEPROM data is meant for the actual type of device. If not, the device goes into an error mode.</Description>
			<Bits>8</Bits>
			<Element>
				<Value>0</Value>
				<Name>BaseStation</Name>
			</Element>
			<Element>
				<Value>20</Value>
				<Name>TempSensor</Name>
			</Element>
			<Element>
				<Value>40</Value>
				<Name>PowerSwitch</Name>
			</Element>
			<Element>
				<Value>60</Value>
				<Name>Dimmer</Name>
			</Element>
			<Element>
				<Value>80</Value>
				<Name>Thermostat</Name>
			</Element>
		</EnumValue>
		<IntValue>
			<ID>OsccalMode</ID>
			<Description>This value is used to change the speed of the internal oscillator. 0 = don't use OSCCAL calibration (e.g. external crystal oszillator is used). -128 = OSCCAL measure mode: the LED blinks every 60s, so the user can measure the original speed. -127..+127 = The speed is adjusted by the given amount in per mill (e.g. 10 means to speed up the device by +1%).</Description>
			<Bits>8</Bits>
			<MinVal>-128</MinVal>
			<MaxVal>127</MaxVal>
		</IntValue>
		<Reserved>
			<Bits>48</Bits>
		</Reserved>
	</Block>
	<Block>
		<Name>Generic</Name>
		<Description>This block contains SHC configuration data which every device has.</Description>
		<UIntValue>
			<ID>DeviceID</ID>
			<Description>The DeviceID identifies the specific unit in the SHC network. It is used to address the device and in messages the device sends. Every device has to have a different DeviceID.</Description>
			<Bits>12</Bits>
			<MinVal>0</MinVal>
			<MaxVal>4095</MaxVal>
		</UIntValue>
		<Reserved>
			<Bits>4</Bits>
		</Reserved>
		<UIntValue>
			<ID>PacketCounter</ID>
			<Description>The PacketCounter is counted up throughout the whole lifetime of the device and is used to make the encrypted packets differently from each other every time.</Description>
			<Bits>24</Bits>
			<MinVal>0</MinVal>
			<MaxVal>16777215</MaxVal>
		</UIntValue>
		<Reserved>
			<Bits>152</Bits>
		</Reserved>
		<ByteArray>
			<ID>AesKey</ID>
			<Description>This key is used to encrypt packets before sending and also used as primary key to decrypt packets. Special devices may have additional keys in their device specific block.</Description>
			<Bytes>32</Bytes>
		</ByteArray>
	</Block>
	<Block>
		<Name>BaseStation</Name>
		<Description>This block contains the specific configuration data that only Base Station devices need.</Description>
		<Restriction>
			<RefID>DeviceType</RefID>
			<Value>0</Value>
		</Restriction>
		<UIntValue>
			<ID>AesKeyCount</ID>
			<Description>This is the number of AES keys to use from the AesKeys block. Limit the number to the needed amount to avoid that the base station tries decoding with every one.</Description>
			<Bits>8</Bits>
			<MinVal>1</MinVal>
			<MaxVal>16</MaxVal>
		</UIntValue>
		<ByteArray>
			<ID>AesKeys</ID>
			<Description>These are all AES keys which can be used to encrypt or decrypt packages at the base station.</Description>
			<Bytes>512</Bytes>
		</ByteArray>
		<Reserved>
			<Bits>3576</Bits>
		</Reserved>
	</Block>
	<Block>
		<Name>TempSensor</Name>
		<Description>This block contains the specific configuration data that only Temperature Sensor devices need.</Description>
		<Restriction>
			<RefID>DeviceType</RefID>
			<Value>20</Value>
		</Restriction>
		<EnumValue>
			<ID>TemperatureSensorType</ID>
			<Description>You can choose one of the supported temperature / humidity sensors. If set to 0, no sensor is used, but the device sends out packets for testing purposes.</Description>
			<Bits>8</Bits>
			<Element>
				<Value>0</Value>
				<Name>NoSensor</Name>
			</Element>
			<Element>
				<Value>1</Value>
				<Name>SHT15</Name>
			</Element>
		</EnumValue>
		<EnumValue>
			<ID>BrightnessSensorType</ID>
			<Description>You can choose one of the supported light sensors. If set to 0, no sensor is used, but the device sends out packets for testing purposes.</Description>
			<Bits>8</Bits>
			<Element>
				<Value>0</Value>
				<Name>NoSensor</Name>
			</Element>
			<Element>
				<Value>1</Value>
				<Name>Photocell</Name>
			</Element>
		</EnumValue>
		<Reserved>
			<Bits>3568</Bits>
		</Reserved>
	</Block>
	<Block>
		<Name>PowerSwitch</Name>
		<Description>This block contains the specific configuration data that only Power Switch devices need.</Description>
		<Restriction>
			<RefID>DeviceType</RefID>
			<Value>40</Value>
		</Restriction>
		<UIntValue>
			<ID>SupportedSwitches</ID>
			<Description>This is a bit field about the connected switches. (Currently, only one switch is supported and the value has to be 0b00000001, but the value is for future usage.)</Description>
			<Bits>8</Bits>
			<MinVal>1</MinVal>
			<MaxVal>1</MaxVal>
		</UIntValue>
		<ByteArray>
			<ID>SwitchState</ID>
			<Description>This field stores the last known switch state(s) for eight switches to allow restoring the same state after power loss. It contains also the remaining timeout value. Fill this with zeros when creating a e2p file!</Description>
			<Bytes>16</Bytes>
		</ByteArray>
		<UIntValue>
			<ID>BaseStationPacketCounter</ID>
			<Description>This is the last remembered packet counter of a command from the base station. Packets with the same or lower number are ignored.</Description>
			<Bits>24</Bits>
			<MinVal>0</MinVal>
			<MaxVal>16777215</MaxVal>
		</UIntValue>
		<Reserved>
			<Bits>7520</Bits>
		</Reserved>
	</Block>
	<Block>
		<Name>Dimmer</Name>
		<Description>This block contains the specific configuration data that only Dimmer devices need.</Description>
		<Restriction>
			<RefID>DeviceType</RefID>
			<Value>60</Value>
		</Restriction>
		<UIntValue>
			<ID>BaseStationPacketCounter</ID>
			<Description>This is the last remembered packet counter of a command from the base station. Packets with the same or lower number are ignored.</Description>
			<Bits>24</Bits>
			<MinVal>0</MinVal>
			<MaxVal>16777215</MaxVal>
		</UIntValue>
		<ByteArray>
			<ID>BrightnessTranslationTable</ID>
			<Description>These are the target values (one byte each) for the input brightness of 0, 1, ... 100% to adapt the specific brightness curve of your lamps. Set first byte to FF to not use it.</Description>
			<Bytes>101</Bytes>
		</ByteArray>
		<Reserved>
			<Bits>6848</Bits>
		</Reserved>
	</Block>
	<Block>
		<Name>Thermostat</Name>
		<Description>This block contains the specific configuration data that only thermostat devices need.</Description>
		<Restriction>
			<RefID>DeviceType</RefID>
			<Value>80</Value>
		</Restriction>
		<UIntValue>
			<ID>BaseStationPacketCounter</ID>
			<Description>This is the last remembered packet counter of a command from the base station. Packets with the same or lower number are ignored.</Description>
			<Bits>24</Bits>
			<MinVal>0</MinVal>
			<MaxVal>16777215</MaxVal>
		</UIntValue>
		<Reserved>
			<Bits>7656</Bits>
		</Reserved>
	</Block>
</E2P>
